Guide to the Julian P. Linke Autograph Collection, 1804-1928
Department of Special Collections
Julian P. Linke Autograph Collection,
1804-1928
Special Collections M0235
Linke, Julian P.
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of the Estate of Julian P. Linke, 1972.
Scope and Content
Description:
Various German, French, and American manuscripts ca. 1804 - 1928. Includes materials of Andrew Carnegie, Thos. Edison, Samuel F. B. Morse, Friedrich Wilhelm III, Wilhelm II, and Karl, Prince of Prussia. Material predominantly in English or German with one item in French.
Container List
- Green notebook from the library of Karl, Prince of Prussia; containing a manuscript account, 32 pages, concerning Napoleon's stay at Potsdam and Berlin. Written by a Prussian gentleman-in-waiting who served Napoleon. (1806) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Andrew CARNEGIE. (1837-1919) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A.L.S. New York. June 7, 1873.
- Thomas A. EDISON. (1847-1931) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A.L.S. Menlo Park. March 7, 1878.To Wm. Orton.
- Ludwig von ERICH. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - L.S. July 21, 1864.
- [Financial Papers] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Two receipts for provisions, Williamsville, 1815.
  - Simon de RIDDER. Two documents signed. Whitehall, N.Y. Sept. 1814.
  - Check drawn on N. Y. State Bank, 1814.
  - Two receipts for whiskey; January 21 and January 28, 1815.
- FREDERICK WILHELM III (1770-1840). Doc. signed. Sept. 24, 1832. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Paul von HINDENBURG. (1847-1934) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - A.L.S. March 4, 1924.
- [KARL, PRINCE OF PRUSSIA] (1801-1883) Guest register, October 4 and 6, 1843;8pages; signed by German, Danish, and British Dukes, Diplomats, Ministers, Generals, etc. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Samuel F. B. MORSE. (1791-1872) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - A.L.S. New York. March 14, 1847.To Amos Kendall.
- Jean Baptiste Donatien de Vimeur, Comte de ROCHAMBEAU, (1725-1807). (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - A.L.S. [Dec. 3, 1804?]
- [West Prussian Corps]. Manuscript booklet. An Account book for August and September, no year. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- WILHELM II. (1859-1941). Letter signed, New Palace, October 31, 1895. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- [WILHELM II]. Rudolf Bloch. Autograph manuscript, not signed. Brooklyn, N.Y. Feb. 27, 1928. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- [WILHELM II]. Letter signed by a court official of Wilhelm II. Doorn, March 15, 1928.To Rudolf Bloch. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- WILHELM II., Postcard photo signed. (Box 1, Folder 15.)